Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
Oh, God.
There you go.
Why didn't you wake me?
- I did. You told me to piss off.
- I don't remember.
- I do.
- All the clocks have stopped in the whole house.
- It's probably just a fuse.
- Oh, Mum, I've got a temperature.
- You haven't.
- I'm not going.
- If I have to, you have to. Doesn't she?
- Not getting involved.
- Ooh-ooh!
- Hi, Mum.
- Morning, Liz.
- Fresh eggs, we had a bumper lay.
- Look at them, eh? Love you zillions.
- OK.
- Er... oi!
- Hello, love.
- I've got a temperature.
- Have you now?
She hasn't.
Gotta go. I'm late to meet Nige.
- Have you seen Danny? He forgot his lunch.
- Probably already gone.
All right. I'm late.
Cheerio, love.
- Get off!
- All right, you lot?
- How's it going? All right?
- My first day back at work, ask me later.
- Sports Day, isn't it? Show 'em what you got.
- I will.
- We should get the lads out.
- Definitely. I'll text you later.
All right, Jen?
Sorry, love. Sorry.
Where were you for five-a-side last
Tuesday?
Sorry. I had to go over to Lyme.
- Mate's band were playing.
- No excuses next time, eh?
Yeah.
- Morning, ladies.
- All right, how are you?
Hey.
- Morning, Oll.
- All right, Mark? How's it going?
Beautiful weather.
Sunshine and showers they reckon.
How's your mum? Is she OK?
Not bad, thanks for asking.
- Pass on my love.
- Yeah, will do, mate. Absolutely.
- Oi, don't you sneak past.
- Knock, knock.
All right, Maggie?
All right, Mark?
- Got your ad renewal for you there, Mag.
- Ah, a week late.
Oh, sorry, no-one's perfect, eh?
Lovely morning for it.
All right, Becca?
Your hotel started
that tradesman's discount yet?
- You've gotta have class to eat here.
- Class? I'm all class, me.
Keep telling yourself that.
- You're late.
- Yeah, sorry, traffic's really stacking up.
There's all them lovely tourist girls
ripe for your picking.
Shut up!
So, what was the upshot of last
night, then?
How about you just drive?
Morning. You all right? Hi. Morning!
Hi, I'm back!
Thank you very much. Quite
right too.
Dom, I got you lung busters,
against my better judgment.
Nish. Look. Vodka, black label.
- Very nice. Thank you.
- Not at all.
- Anna, I got you lip gloss for all your kissing.
- Thank you.
- Mike... moisturizer. Give that lovely face a lift.
I got you a cuddly penguin, Frank.
I know you get lonely.
Come on, then. What's all the
gossip?
Ellie. Welcome back. Can I have a
quick word?
- What's the news?
- We've given the job to someone else.
- What?
- I know it's a disappointment.
You said it'd wait till I got back from leave.
You said I was a shoo-in. That's why I took 3 weeks!
- The situation changed.
- Christ!
- Who? Who got it?
- DI Alec Hardy.
A man?
What happened to "The area
needs a female DI"?
What happened to "I've got your
backing"?
- Alec Hardy has a lot of experience.
- Why do I know that name?
He was in charge of the Sandbrook
murders.
Are you kidding me?
- When does he start?
- Last week.
You wanna see this or not?
Yep, OK. Received.
That's where they cut to get in.
Siphoned the whole bloody tank.
We'll be in touch.
Is that it?
What about forensics?
I can't afford this, the price of
diesel.
- You called me at seven in the morning for that.
- Too good for it, are you?
Just got a call. Coast Guard reported
something down by the shore.
After all she said to me, what's the
bloody point?
Shall I just walk out, clear my desk
and go?
No, I know. But you should have seen
me, I was so happy coming back.
I'm in here!
Ellie, you've got a shout.
Gotta go.
- Can you see Danny? I can't see him.
- He'll be with his class.
I can't believe you're making me
come to this.
Hey, your choice. Stay here or get
on to your own school.
- Oh, all right. I'll go in.
- I love you very much.
And if you remember that smile
give it a go for me, would you?
Usain Bolt. OK?
Now all look egg-cited.
Hiya.
All right?
Beth? No Danny?
Oh, I thought he was here.
No, we haven't seen him today.
- Well, did you do the register?
- Yeah, we haven't seen him since yesterday.
Miss?
Danny, it's Mum. So, you're not at school.
Can you give me a call straightaway, sweetheart?
I just wanna know where you are.
Jack, it's Beth. Danny did his paper
round this morning, right?
Oh, er... OK. Did he ring?
No, no, no, it's fine. I'm just...
just not quite sure where he is, that's all.
Mark, it's me. Ring me now.
Tom? Tom!
Danny didn't say he was going
anywhere this morning, did he?
It's alright, he's not in trouble.
- OK. Thank you.
- Can I do anything?
- Just give me a call if he shows up.
- Yeah, sure.
Hey, Tom.
Oh, come on. Come on.
Main road to the coast
at Broadchurch.
If you are heading to the beach
I suggest you make other plans.
- What's going on?
- Someone said the police are at the beach.
They might have found a body.
Stand back. Stand back, please.
Oh, God, don't do this to me.
Come on.
- Oh, God. No, no, no.
- Off the beach.
- This area's off-limits.
- No, I'm police.
Oh, God, I know him. He lives here.
He has tea at my house.
He's my boy's best friend.
- Oh, God, Beth. Does Beth know?
- All right, calm down, DS Miller
- You don't understand. I know that boy.
- Shut it off.
- "Shut it off"?
- Be professional. You're working a case now.
- Alec Hardy.
- I know. You got my job.
- Really? You wanna do that now?
- You don't even know who he is.
Tell me!
Danny. Daniel Latimer. 11 years old.
Goes to school with my boy Tom.
His family live here. Dad's the
local plumber.
- Is this a suicide spot?
- He wouldn't do that.
Answer the question.
No.  There are others - one three miles
west; another one further inland.
He's not that type of kid.
Find out where SOCO are.
We have to move fast.
That tide'll be in.
Oh, God.
Oh, God. Who's that?
- No, Beth, get off the beach.
- What have you found?
- Let me see, let me see.
- You can't be here!
- Stop. Get her off the beach. Get her away from here.
- Those are his shoes.
- Come on, come on.
- Those are Danny's trainers!
No!
Danny!
- Ah, Olly, you're back.
- Survived Sports Day.
Not only that - coffees.
- Ah.
- That's three shots.
Double-page spread. Spell all the
children's names correctly, please.
I don't want the parents berating me.
So, Reg didn't turn up. Red Lion.
- What, you mean we've got no pictures?
- Ah.
Camera phone. I took them myself.
Ah... good initiative, Olly.
Show me how to download these?
Why do still use Reg?
He always lets you down.
I see Reg in the supermarket every
Saturday. We look after our own here.
Oh, look at their little faces.
Oh, that's very nice. You've almost
got an eye.
I tell Reg I'm using camera phone
pictures in the paper.
He'll be back and sober within the
hour.
Oh, my God. It's the Daily Mail.
It's my application.
Open it.
Bastards!
Oh, sweetheart.
- There's plenty of other newspapers.
- I've tried them all now.
You're good, petal. Your time will
come.
Now, look, text from Yvonne.
She says the beach is closed off
for some reason.
Go down, check it out, will you?
Get yourself some fresh air.
Sure.
They let people walk along
here, no safety barriers?
It's a coastal path. People know to
be careful.
It's a death trap.
- How's it going?
- Well, from what we've got up here, sir,
it looks like the rock fall
around the body was faked.
What do you mean?
The angle of the body was wrong.
It was too arranged.
And up here there's no flattened
grass or slippage.
No loose rocks. No fibres, no hand
marks.
- No sense of a downward trajectory.
- You mean he didn't fall?
Could he have jumped?
That's unlikely, sir, given where he
was found and the trajectory
off the cliffs.
See, not Danny.
If you ask me... someone tried to
make it look like an accident.
I don't think he was up here.
Get on to the pathologist. Tell him
to hurry up.
Even if it is just preliminary.
- DS Miller!
- Who's that?
- Just keep walking.
- Ellie!
- He seems to know you.
- Auntie Ellie.
- I told you, don't do that.
- Olly Stevens, Broadchurch Echo.
I was down at the other end.  They said you'd
be here. Why has the beach been closed?
No statements now.
I heard there was a body. Has it
been ID'd?
- Please.
- There will be a statement, Oliver.
- Are they all in there?
- Sir, I can lead this with the family.
No.
- I know them.
- How many deaths like this have you worked?
- This is my first.
- You can't make it better. Don't try.
- You don't know how I work.
- Most likely premise is abduction.
Was he taken? If so, who by?
Watch them. Every movement.
If anything doesn't make sense you
tell me.
OK.
Don't look at me like that.
Morning.
I'm Detective Inspector Alec Hardy
and you know DS Miller.
Why don't you take a seat? We need
to talk about something. Yeah.
Sit down.
Get a chair.
Don't worry, I can do it.
- The body of a young boy was found...
- It's Danny, isn't it?
- I saw his shoes.
- Plenty of kids have those shoes.
Sorry. You talk.
We believe it's Danny's body.
Who is it, Ellie? Was it him?
Hey.
Hey, it's all right.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
- Was it an accident? Did he fall?
- We don't know yet.
Can you think why he might have been up
on the cliffs last night or this morning?
- He wouldn't have been.
- Well, he obviously was.
He didn't have any reason to be.
How was Danny over the past few
days?
He didn't kill himself
if that's what you're suggesting.
He's been just... normal.
He wouldn't kill himself. He knows
he can talk to us about anything.
And you last saw him when?
I looked in on him er...
about nine o'clock last night.
He was laying in bed reading.
Anyone see Danny this morning?
No. He was up and out before anyone
else. He's got a paper round.
But he didn't turn up for that.
Jack, I spoke to him.
He runs the paper shop.
Any signs of forced entry
or disturbance round the house?
No, nothing.
I wanna see the body.
You might be wrong about it being
him.
So, I wanna be sure. I wanna see.
- How many times you done this, Ell?
- I haven't.
Thanks a lot.
Mark! All right, buddy?
All right, Trev?
What you in here for? Nothing
serious, I hope?
- Nah.
- Sign this petition, will you?
- They're threatening to close this place down.
- In a bit of a rush.
Oh, come on. Won't take two seconds.
It's important.
Ah, good man. Hey, coming to
skittles, the Lion on Tuesday?
The Yetminster. Grudge match.
I don't know, mate.
See how it goes, eh? Right. Give my
love to Beth and the kids.
All this way I thought it wouldn't
be him.
My Danny.
Can I touch him, Ell?
Why him, eh, Ell?
He's only little, isn't he? He's
just...
He's just my little boy, isn't he?
Listen, boy.
Er...
I'm... I'm sorry that I
er...
that I wasn't there for you and
You're... you're my...
You're my boy, Danny, and I let you
down.
I'm so, so sorry.
I love you zillions, superstar.
I always will.
Was Danny Latimer abducted?
Did someone gain access to the house?
If so, how?
If it wasn't forced entry, who has
the key?
We need to collect any CCTV
from a mile radius around the house.
Miller - family.
Who are they and where were they?
Beth had Chloe, their eldest
daughter, when she was 15.
Mark was 17.
Mum and daughter were at home
watching telly.
They say they didn't leave the house
until school next morning.
Dad was out on an emergency
call-out. He's a plumber.
He got in around three. Neither
parent thought to check on Danny.
Gran lives nearby. She was in all
evening. The other gran lives
in Wales.
Until we're ready all of this remains
confidential.
No gossip. Do you understand?
All right. Go on.
Given the nature of this case
it makes sense to hand it on to
another lead officer.
No.
It's nothing to do with your
ability. We don't want Sandbrook
to become a thing.
I was completely exonerated.
Alec, you came down here to lie low.
I came to do whatever the job
requires.
But in terms of public perception,
you may be vulnerable.
I'm giving you the chance to step
back. Nobody will blame you.
This happened
a stone's throw from your station.
I've met your team. No-one's as
qualified as me.
Sandbrook doesn't make me vulnerable.
It makes me the best man for the job.
You wanna stop me, you're welcome to
try.
Thanks for the 99.
What did Jenkinson want?
Jenkinson?
The Chief Super. I saw you walking
with her. No.
I did, you were having 99s. Miller,
your son went to school with Danny.
Does he know yet?
No.
You need to talk to him.
Tomorrow. I'll tell him tonight.
And, sir, do you mind not calling me
Miller?
Why? I don't really like the surname
thing.
I prefer Ellie.
Ellie.
Ellie. No.
Jack, we need to ask you a few
questions.
Danny didn't turn up for his round
this morning?
I assumed he was sick.
Did he often miss his round?
They all do, one time or another.
How was Danny yesterday?
No different from usual.
You didn't notice anything on his
mind?
He was only in here 15 minutes first
thing. I'm no psychiatrist.
Are you married?
No.
Are you?
They brought him in here, Mark and
Beth.
Three days old, he was.
It's not right.
What do you have? Superficial cuts
and bruises to the face.
Traces of domestic cleaning fluid on
the skin.
Cause of death was asphyxiation.
He was strangled.
Bruising to the neck and windpipe
and at the top of the spine.
The pattern of bruises suggest large
hands.
I'd suggest er... male.
It erm... it would have been brutal.
The angle suggests he would have
been facing his attacker.
Er... He would have known.
Any sexual violence?
Mercifully, no.
The time of death?
Er, I'd put it between 10pm Thursday
night and 4am Friday morning.
Thank you.
We don't get these around here.
Make sure you find them.
We have some preliminary
findings.
We are treating Danny's death
as suspicious.
Oh.
We think he may have been killed.
I should have checked on him
before I went to bed.
If I'd checked...
Beth, this is not your fault.
Whatever happened, this is not down
to you.
I promise...
we will find the person responsible.
Oh, my God.
You have my word.
He's a little boy.
Chlo, I don't know what to say.
I know.
It doesn't feel real.
Are the police round?
Come on, let's go. I want to do this.
Seriously?
What did they ask you?
Do they know about us? Cos you ain't
16 yet.
Nobody knows. Let's go.
Are you OK?
I'll be better once I've eaten
something.
Do you want anything?
No.
Do you think other kids are in
danger?
I don't know.
Maybe.
Are you sure you're OK?
Do you want me to do it?
Hello?
Is it Danny Latimer?
I can't talk to you.
I've seen Chloe at the beach. It is,
isn't it? This isn't appropriate,
Oliver.
It is him. Oh, my God. The poor kid.
I did not confirm that. This is not a
confirmation.
No, I understand, Auntie Ellie.
Olly...
Hi, it's Olly. Leave a message.
Answer my bloody calls. I did not
confirm that.
You cannot speculate about this
incident. Are we clear?
Karen, you might want to see this.
Not now, Sam.
I've this Department of Education
press release that's got to sound
like essential news.
It's barely in English.
Who teaches these people?
You said tell you if anything comes
on the local paper Twitter feeds.
Go on, then, quick.
Body found on Dorset beach.
Young boy, possible suspicious
death.
OK. Have you got a link you can send
me?
Already did.
You already did.
Thanks.
This is how grateful I am. I'm going
to give you the last of my muffin.
So how's it going?
Great. Two minutes.
I'm going to take Danny's computer
away for examination.
Will they get it back? Sure, as soon
as we've finished with it.
It's got his stuff on it.
We'll be careful.
Why have you released his name?
Did you agree to that?
What?
It's on Twitter. From the
Broadchurch Echo. Daniel Latimer.
Why have they done that?
Talk to the officer in charge.
Nobody told us this was going to
happen.
Aren't they supposed to consult?
How do you know anyway?
I've got a Google alert
on "Broadchurch" and "death".
Oh, for goodness' sake, Chloe!
Well, it's a good job I have
otherwise we wouldn't have known.
Known what?
For God's sake!
Bloody Twitter!
These people's lives have been
destroyed
and now our incompetence has made it
worse.
Think what we have to do now
to rebuild trust there.
Who told the journalist?
I think it might have been me.
Your nephew?
He saw Danny's sister at the beach.
I didn't tell him anything. I told
him not to publish. He's a
little shit.
I'll read the riot act and I'll
explain to the family.
Go away.
Shit, shit, shit, shit! Shit!
Hi, Nick.
Ma'am.
This is a short statement
to confirm that this morning
the body of an 11-year-old child
was found on Harbour Cliff Beach
at Broadchurch.
The body was subsequently identified
as Daniel Latimer,
who lived in the town.
We are treating his death as
suspicious.
Our investigations are continuing and
there'll be a full briefing later
this evening.
We ask the media respect the family's
privacy at this time. Thank you.
Can you believe it?
He got another job even after
Sandbrook.
Boss... Suspicious death.
Kid on Dorset beach.
Gender? Age? Boy. 11. I want to go
down. There could be...
Not for that. It's the wrong profile.
It'll cost too much.
Let an agency do it. You can jazz it
up.
Oh, come on, all I'm doing these
days is polishing press releases.
Pretty please.
Hello.
Hi.
Long day?
Yeah.
It's really tragic.
Can't bear to think what the family
must be going through. We're all
in shock.
Actually, do you think the beach
will be open tomorrow? I...
Only so I know what to tell the
guests. I don't know.
I've had an early check-out and
a cancellation just tonight. So...
I'm going up.
Oh, sorry, there's two people
waiting for you in the bar.
Well, go on.
I was wrong to post that news. I'm
sorry.
I should hang him by the bollocks
from the town hall spire.
All reporting on this will come
through me now.
The Echo works with the police.
I'll... I'll speak to the Latimer
family.
Give them our apologies.
Stay out of my way.
Thanks for bringing me.
I used to come down here when he was
a baby.
Middle of the day, just me and him.
I'd pick him up and dip him in the
waves.
His little fat legs would be all
wet.
God, he loved it. He laughed like
mad.
I used to do the same with Tom.
Does he know?
Promise me, Ellie, because...
I don't know your boss from Adam
and me and you go back...
The boys go back.
I'm counting on you to get them
caught.
I swear.
He did know, didn't he?
That I loved him.
Of course he did.
He was a beautiful boy, Beth.
You don't deserve this.
I just... I just feel... like...
very far away from myself.
Here's Mummy!
Look at you still up.
And eating yoghurt.
You love yoghurt, especially wearing
it.
I'm only here for a shower.
I've got to get back.
Are things bad?
Need a hug?
How was your day?
Or shouldn't I ask?
Second go at tea. First one was
a bit of an apocalypse, wasn't it?
Thank you, Mummy.
And I'm still smiling.
Oh, no, Mummy.
Thank you.
Where's Tom?
In bed.
Does he know?
No.
I got the text, kept him away from
it all.
I can't...
Do you know what happened? Should we
be worried, for other kids?
Don't know yet.
I'll go up and tell him in a minute.
How's the new boss?
Come here.
It's all right.
It's not all right.
Come here.
I saw him lying there. I don't think
I can do this.
You can.
I keep thinking he's going to walk
back in.
Every time my phone goes, I think
it's Danny.
Why didn't you look in on him last
night?
Beth...
You always look in on him when you
come to bed. Why didn't you see
he was gone?
Why didn't you?
Where were you last night?
I told you. I was on a job.
You know Danny wasn't at school
today?
Yeah.
Tom, sweetheart...
Danny died.
I'm so sorry.
How?
I don't know yet.
He was found on the beach early this
morning.
Does his mum and dad know?
Yeah.
So, look, when...
When someone dies unexpectedly...
it leaves a big hole.
And it's all right to be sad or to
have a cry, OK?
OK.
Will you...? I mean...
Will the police want to ask me
questions?
Yeah.
Is there anything you want to tell me
now?
Was Danny all right?
Yeah.
Of course.
I think a hug's a good idea.
You know I love you more than
anything?
More than chocolate?
Even more than chocolate.
I'll be just downstairs.
And don't be embarrassed to have that
cry.
Hello?
Hi, Olly. It's Karen White from the
Daily Herald.
Oh, um, hi.
I saw you broke the story about Danny
Latimer.
I'm down here after a hotel
recommendation.
Oh, right, OK. Where are you at the
moment? The beach.
I see people have started leaving
flowers.
Danny's sister left one of his toys
down there. It must have started it.
Um, OK, so your best option is the
Traders Hotel.
It's opposite our offices on the
high street.
Becca runs it. Tell her you know us,
she'll give you a good rate.
Great. Thanks.
I'll maybe see you around.
Yeah, I hope so, yeah.
I mean, that would...
Who are you putting up at
the Traders? No-one. A girl, woman.
Oh, a woman?
I'm off to the media briefing at the
school. Good luck.
Not that you...
I know.
Different suit?
Press conference in 10 minutes.
Look at this. CCTV from town centre
last night.
Is that Danny?
It matches his clothes, height. It
looks like his skateboard.
He wasn't abducted.
He snuck out.
Why? Where was he going?
Who was he meeting?
And where's his skateboard?
Yeah.
I was checking through the list of
belongings recovered from Danny's
body and at home
and there's no mobile phone.
He definitely had one. He and Tom,
my son, had the same model,
virtually identical.
It isn't there?
No.
Check with the family.
Good.
I'm going to hand over now to our
senior investigating officer
DI Alec Hardy.
What advice do you have for people in
the town, particularly parents?
The crime rate in this area
is one of the lowest in the country.
This is a terrible anomaly.
We are in the early moments of what
might be a complex investigation.
Danny's life touched many people and
we'll be looking at all those
connections.
If you or someone you know
has any information,
has noticed anything unusual,
please come forward now.
Um, I'd urge everyone, don't hide
anything...
because we will find out.
If a member of your family or a
friend or a neighbour
has been behaving differently
in the past days or weeks,
please tell the police immediately.
There will be no hiding place for
Danny's killer.
We will catch whoever did this.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
www.tvsubtitles.net