***
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
I remember that day
very clearly.
I was sitting right where
you are sitting today.
I was ready
to knock down the door,
to kick some righteous ass.
[Laughter]
Just like you.
I just knew I was
the smartest, the fastest,
the best this institution
had to offer.
And then...
And then I stepped
into the real world.
[Soul music]
♪
We are here today to honor
the 50 newest agents
of the federal bureau
of investigation.
I'm talking to you,
ladies and gentlemen,
because inside these walls,
you all are the best
of the best.
But I just want to take
just a moment
to think about what's going
to happen outside these walls.
You all are walking off
one battlefield in here
and onto another battlefield
out there.
The difference being,
the battlefield out there
is real,
and the dangers are real.
[Soul music continues]
[Music stops]
Ÿcomo estan, amigos?
[Speaking Spanish]
[Speaking spanish] Ah, sputnik.
Everything
you've acquired of value
in your short time
on this earth,
everything you are worth
is locked inside of you,
and that means, at this moment,
you find yourself
in the unique position
you may never be in again:
You have nothing to lose.
Let's cook it up!
I'll leave you with this:
Whatever you think
success means,
I hope you'll stay open
to the possibility
that you've got it all wrong...
That you have
absolutely no idea
what life has got
in store for you.
You will make mistakes.
You are not perfect.
Esta LA buena.
You will fail.
And when the day comes
and you figure it out,
I hope you'll have
the brains, the guts,
and the straight up good luck
to survive it.
Nyet!
[Overlapping yelling]
[Coughs]
[Men yelling]
[Tires screeching]
Congratulations.
You are now agents
of the federal bureau
of investigation.
[Cheers and applause]
Do me proud.
[Cheers and applause, chatter]
[Cheers and applause]
[Knocking] Hey, yo, Briggs!
Hey.
Come on, time to get up, man.
We got 5' sets comin' in.
Get out, Johnny.
I have a gun.
[Scoffs] Yeah? So do I.
Come on, let's go.
Come on, man.
Now, is that cool?
You told me
no matter what you said
or how ugly you got
not to let you sleep in, right?
I'd been awake 32 hours
when I said that.
So what?
No, if I let you nod off,
you're just gonna yell at me
'cause I didn't do
what you said. Let's go.
[Knocking]
Dang it, man.
[Knocking at door]
No.
God, I'm sorry, Paul.
Were you sleeping?
Should I come back later?
[Sighs]
You know, boss,
that would be swell.
No. No, no.
It's time to rise and shine.
Lauren! Tuturro!
What a dick.
- What?
- Yo.
Need you to get Donnie's stuff
out of his room.
- Donnie's not dead.
- For what?
I didn't say he was dead.
I said his stuff was in the way.
We got a new agent coming in.
You got two hours.
What?
Hell, no.
That's Donnie's room.
You're not replacing Donnie,
and I'm going back to bed,
so you guys...
No, you're not.
He's your new trainee.
Name's Mike Warren.
Graduated top of his class
at Quantico.
So did Briggs, and he can't
even match his socks.
These aren't my socks.
1700 on his practicals?
Yeah, your record still stands.
Lauren, where are you going?
- Don't worry about it.
- What, he's got a 1700?
Is he, like, a savant,
or something?
Uh, boss,
does anybody happen to notice
the kid doesn't speak Spanish?
Yeah.
They're putting him through
linguistics training now.
Lauren!
[Speaking Spanish]
He runs a 440 mile. I was
doing that in the fifth grade.
Yeah,
but you're a stud, Johnny.
- True.
- His plane lands at 0800.
Briggs, be there
to pick him up.
Okay.
- 0800.
- Yes, sir.
Johnny, need you
to go to the airport.
Nah, man, no.
It's my day off.
I don't want to spend
all morning in some terminal.
And there's no picture, so I'm...
Yeah, well, you know,
make a sign or something.
He's an undercover.
You can't make a sign.
Can I?
I'm going surfing.
How am I supposed to
find this guy?
I don't know.
Be a problem-solver, Johnny.
Be mexcellent.
[Chuckles]
And scramble me some eggs,
por favor?
What a dick.
"LA comida esta muy buena."
Oh, [Speaking Spanish]
Oh. [Laughs] I'm sorry.
I don't speak Spanish.
Oh. You said
you like the food.
Yeah, it's...
ah, you're learning Espanol.
Si.
[Both laugh]
It's a job requirement.
I thought I was going to D.C.,
and then, last minute, I'm...
well, I'm headed to California.
Oh, what do you do?
I'm a teacher.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- So's my brother.
- Yeah?
- What school?
- It's... it's a new one.
- Oh.
- Yeah, it's brand-new.
It... It doesn't have a name yet.
Oh.
- Yeah.
- Excuse me, sir?
Are you special agent
Mike Warren with the FBI?
Yeah.
This message was patched to you
through the cockpit phone:
"Agent Warren, wait
under the baggage claim sign
"in terminal 'C' for your
field training agent to arrive.
Do not leave the baggage area
under any circumstances."
Thank you.
Uh
manos arriba.
[Chuckles] Excuse me?
It means, "hands up."
It's probably not
on your lessons.
Passengers arriving on
flight 26 from Dulles, Virginia,
your luggage will be available
on baggage claim C.
Excuse me.
[Folksy tune]
♪
This is the final boarding
call for all passengers
on flight number 122.
♪
[P.A. in background]
[Chuckles]
Mike Warren, right?
Yeah.
You wanna know how I knew that?
Uh, 'cause I was told to wait
underneath this sign and I am?
No, because only a guy who got
a 1700 on his practicals
and was told
to wait under a sign
is still gonna be waiting there
two hours later.
Where's agent Briggs?
Who says I ain't Briggs?
Well, you just said "1700"
like you were impressed.
Paul Briggs got
a higher score than I did,
so from that, I would conclude
that... You didn't.
[Both laugh]
I'm tuturro.
Everybody calls me Johnny.
Dude,
what's with the hand thing?
Oh, it improves gun control.
Okay, yeah.
[Spanish pop music]
♪
[Snippets of Spanish radio]
Hey, what are you listening to?
Oh, it's Spanish,
for the language requirement.
[Chuckles] It's a bitch,
right? How you getting it?
[Speaking Spanish]
[Chuckles] That's good.
Dude, this place
is a melting pot.
Hey, ladies.
[Speaking korean]
[Both laugh]
No? No?
[Laughs]
What did you say to them?
I said,
no matter what they say,
I'm gonna hold it against them.
[Both laugh]
But you surf?
No.
- You got shorts?
- No.
- Flips?
- No. What?
- Sunscreen?
- No.
God, your white ass
is gonna burn.
All right,
you gotta go shopping, okay?
- Okay.
- All right.
Mike? Mike!
Do the people around here know?
- What, that we're feds?
- Yeah.
No. No, we tell 'em
different things.
Briggs tells people
he's a Tae Bo instructor.
Charlie says
she's a trust fund kid.
Yo, one chick I'm dating
thinks I'm a lear jet pilot.
- She believes that?
- Yeah, she...
dude, you see this?
Lear jet key.
Looks like a bike lock.
You are smarter
than the chick I'm dating.
[Both laugh]
Tell me about Briggs.
He's the best agent
I ever seen.
That's what I hear, man.
This is it. Not bad, huh?
[Chuckles]
Hey, why do they call it
"Graceland"?
When they seized it
from this drug lord,
he was apparently
some hard-core Elvis fan,
and when they turned it
into a flop house for us,
the name just kinda stuck.
Hey, be glad you're not
moving in a lot of stuff, bro.
[Chuckles]
All right, so you, me,
Briggs, and Charlie are FBI.
Lauren and Donnie are DEA.
So is Paige,
but she's on a case
for a couple days.
Oh, and Jakes.
Jakes is customs.
It works, having
three agencies in one house?
We all start to blend together
after a while.
Oh, if you have civilians over,
they stay down here, okay?
Nobody's allowed past
those stairs without a badge.
So no local girls upstairs.
I know... I know it sucks.
Yo, you know what this is?
Looks like a chore wheel.
You are smart.
We all take turns cleaning.
Dishes, toilets, all that.
For now,
wherever it says "Donnie,"
you write in your name.
- Donnie's the DEA guy who...
- Got shot?
- Yeah.
Is he all right?
He's alive.
That's about all we know
right now.
They got him locked away
in some safe house, so...
but good news is he doesn't have
to clean the bathrooms tomorrow.
So mop's in the hall closet,
brother.
Come on, Mikey.
[Phone ringing]
Okay, dude. This?
This is the phone room.
This is where you'll make
all your UC calls.
Do not...
Out!
[Phone ringing]
[Russian accent] Hello?
That's Lauren.
Donnie was her partner.
That sucks.
[Speaking Russian]
Donnie was
under the Gallardo cartel
out of Tijuana.
He was doing a needle drop.
What's that?
Well, they expect him to test
the quality of the heroin
by shooting up.
Right.
So he pretends
to inject himself.
But what he's really doing
is sticking the needle
in a little rubber ball
he's got tucked into his arm.
Ball popped out, they shot him.
- Damn.
- Yeah. Be that way sometimes.
Hey, Briggs!
I got your new guy out here.
[Bang on door]
Yeah, um...
You'll meet him later.
Let's check out your room.
Pretty dope, right?
Yeah.
Hey. Mike Warren.
New guy.
This is my partner's room.
Don't touch anything.
Don't get comfortable.
Okay.
You play tennis.
[Cocks gun]
Yes.
Yo, don't worry about her.
For real.
But maybe don't move a lot
of Donnie's stuff at first.
Yo, find me later.
We'll grab something to eat.
Thanks, Johnny.
[Bird cawing]
No, no, man.
It's a golden conure.
I know that.
Every white couple
in the valley, man,
they pay you 2,000!
All right, I'ma give you 200
for them, final price.
No, man.
We cool, man, yeah?
250.
All right, you have a deal.
But all of the birds,
they better talk.
And that's that.
Just like my wife.
- So she talk and talk.
- And talk and talk.
- Your wife can't shut up.
- No, she can't.
You know this, man.
I have to live with her.
- You know her.
- Okay?
- Respect.
- Respect, yes.
Gonna get a new home, huh?
You too.
I don't like you.
- How you doing, sweetheart?
- Hi.
Feel free to grab
some more juice, dude.
- Thanks.
- Take all you want, it's yours.
What's all this?
Yo, Jakes.
Mike Warren, bureau.
He's taking Donnie's room.
You work customs.
Johnny told me
that you were working on
a bird smuggling operation.
I didn't realize
that was such a problem
here on the west coast.
It is.
Half a million birds a year.
Wow!
Yeah, you also gotta watch out
for the bird flu, right, Jakes?
Yeah, a virus can take down
a whole city.
That's my juice, man.
Excuse me?
Do you see a "D" and "J" on it?
Oh.
D.J.
I thought it was an "O."
I thought
someone labeled it O.J.
- O.J.
- Yeah.
The guy who killed
the white woman.
- No, I didn't...
- Dale Jakes.
D.J.
Just like this D.J.
You check the milk,
guess what you gonna find.
D.J.?
Yep, just like everything else
on that top shelf.
Sorry.
Do I look like your frat buddy?
- Nope.
- Am I one of your college pals?
It won't happen again.
It looked like an "O"
to me, man.
I don't know why
he's messing with...[Mutters].
Your new boy ate my cereal.
Mm.
What's up?
What's up, man?
You must be Warren.
Yes, sir.
You're agent Briggs.
Mmhmm.
Ha ha!
I'm honored to be training
with you, sir.
Excellent.
- Oh, I'm ready to begin.
- Now?
Oh, yes, sir.
Good attitude, Warren.
Um, you familiar
with the chore wheel?
- Yes, sir.
- Okay.
To get you started,
wherever it says "Briggs"
I want you to substitute Mike.
It'll help you with the whole
undercover
name association thing.
So tonight,
where it says "dishes, Briggs"
I want you to think...
Both: "Dishes, Mike."
- 1700 on your practicals.
- Yeah.
Think of it as a whole
wax on, wax off sort of thing.
Now if you gentlemen
will excuse me,
I'm off in pursuit
of the perfect bottle of rum.
Bingo.
That's Paul Briggs?
That's Briggs.
[Man coughing]
[Baby crying]
- Yo!
- What?
Get up!
You wanna watch him?
Mmmm.
- He's your kid.
- I'll watch him.
- You want some?
- Nah. Gotta make rent, man.
[Baby crying]
FBI.
I wanna see your hands.
- You the new guy?
- What?
No guns downstairs.
I'm taking back my 20.
There's no guns downstairs.
- Who's that?
- That's Charlie.
Some damn good gun control
you got there, bro.
Did I scare you?
No. Why?
No.
Where's your stuff?
Lauren suggested
I don't unpack, so...
I see.
You know,
I didn't even get a key.
Well...
Donnie keeps a spare.
Thank you.
Hey, uh,
tell Lauren about that...
I will shoot you.
Yes, ma'am.
- Bye.
[Phone ringing]
[Sighs, groans]
Who's this?
Who do you think it is?
Hey, darling.
They took all my cells.
I don't have any caller I.D.
They got you back
in the stone age.
How's the new place?
It's a safe house.
It's safe, boring as hell.
Got a gun and a badge
and no place to go.
Nurse once a day
for the gunshots.
- She hot?
- Yeah, tall and nordic.
Do an hour of pt a day,
then back to being bored.
The Russians
still want me dead?
Uh, they're on radio silence,
but you gotta figure.
Mexicans want you dead too.
Yeah.
So you give away my room yet?
It's not a done deal.
What!
They gave away my room?
Okay, there's
this new bureau guy in, but...
man, that's cold.
[Scoffs]
Not like I'm dead.
I told him not to touch
your stuff.
It's not Graceland without you.
Get strong.
Yeah.
I never let that damn ball drop,
Lauren, you know?
I know.
Hey, Warren!
Get up.
[Off-notes twang]
[Sighs]
Yo, Briggs!
You were supposed
to wake me up, sucka!
[Cackling]
[Pop music]
♪
All right, Mikey.
It's a South swell
with a 5-foot face.
It breaks left,
so steer clear of the pier
or you're gonna get slammed.
Right, South swell,
don't get slammed on the pier.
Uh, why is it important
we do this?
Because when you catch
that ride,
better than sex.
True.
[Laughing]
This is about learning how
to control your energy, okay?
Understanding
your body's connection
to the things around it.
Better than sex?
- Not in my world.
- Sometimes.
[Laughing]
All right.
Let's hit it, Poseidon.
[Pop music]
♪
- Any advice?
- Yeah, when you feel
that swell coming up under you,
get on that board and surf.
[Laughing, murmurs]
♪
Ha. Come on, boy.
Come on, boy, drop it.
Hey, I just...
I just bought that.
Hey.
[Dog growls]
I'm not in the mood for...
mood for this.
Oh!
Enjoying yourself?
No, I'm not.
[Sighs] Look at him.
You know, at Quantico,
they talk about him
like he's some sort of God.
I mean, a ga award
and a director's award
before he's 30?
I mean, he had more stats
in his first year
than his whole squad combined.
So you were expecting somebody
a little more button-down,
suit and tie-ish?
Yeah, something like that.
He was like that once.
Yeah.
[Scoffs]
A few years ago,
something went down.
He took a leave of absence,
came back all zenned out
like that.
- You don't know what happened?
- Nope.
He never talks about it.
You're not curious?
Maybe he's just crazy.
Totalmente loco, si.
Oh, your Spanish
is coming along.
- Ah, you like that?
- It's all right.
The house is a tight fit.
You're gonna find out real fast
there are no secrets
at Graceland.
- Except for Briggs.
- Yeah, except for Briggs.
That wave's about
to get its ass kicked.
Kill it, Mike.
[Mellow pop music]
♪
You almost got up.
That's a hell of a start.
I've never felt anything
like that before.
I could literally feel the wave
right through my board.
- Briggs!
- Yo.
You got a message
from a guy named Felix arroyo.
You checking my messages now?
He wants to make a buy
this morning.
Yeah, uh, he's off
our active list, Lauren.
Seriously, are you checking
my messages now?
I know his 202.
He works for Vzakonye.
Works for... he probably does
their gardening, bro.
He works for Vzakonye.
He was a low-level dealer,
Lauren.
We tapped him,
he dropped a few Russian names.
That's it.
You know that.
Come on, Briggs.
They shot Donnie.
Felix didn't.
Anything I can get
on these guys...
[Sighs]
- Go like this.
- Yeah, yeah.
That's more like it.
You're lucky
you have those eyes.
Mike.
Yeah?
How'd you like to do
a reverse this morning?
Do what?
He wants to buy
8 yards of indoor.
Indoor.
What's indoor?
Uh, "indoor carpet" is Felix's
code word for cocaine.
Yard's a key.
Call in to ops?
No, no, Johnny.
It's better to beg forgiveness
than to ask permission.
You know that.
[Laughs]
[Phone ringing]
- Yo!
- Felix, it's Paul.
Got your message, man.
What's up?
Hey, Paul.
que pasa?
Nada mucho.
que tal?
Thought he was Russian.
No, he's Mexican.
He just works for them.
His wife's Russian.
Dude, I told you.
Melting pot, right?
Can you... can you hook me up
with 8 yards of the indoor?
20 a yard?
No can do, compadre.
Come on, man.
You said you could hook me up
anytime I needed it.
I got people counting on me.
Man.
Yeah. Yeah, I got somebody
who can bring it by.
- Your amigo is mi amigo.
- All right.
Your casa, two hours.
Orale!
I'll see him then.
Surf's up.
Where we setting up?
The techs found us this vacant
a block away from Felix's.
- Cool.
- Yeah, should be good.
- All right, agent Warren.
- Yeah?
This is gonna be
a simple reverse, okay?
You're gonna walk in,
you're gonna make the deal,
you're gonna give us
the bust signal.
Okay, what's my name?
- Uh, your name is Mike.
- Yeah?
Go with Mike.
[Laughter] Right.
A last name?
Don't give him
a last name, Mike.
"No... Last..."
Hey, why-why...
why did you do that?
Because you can't take
a crib sheet with you, okay?
Look, just keep it simple.
See, bad guys don't tend
to ask a lotta questions
because they don't want you
asking a lotta questions.
You feel me?
How do you and I know
each other if he asks?
If he asks,
just say "around."
We can make it
a little interesting.
Put him in the movie.
No, man!
Why not?
That contradicts
everything I just said, John.
- So what?
- Um, what movie?
- It's nothing.
- I'll tell it!
No.
[Scoffs] All right, look.
The Colima, right...
these guys are hard-core.
Type of dudes that'll shoot you
just to make sure
that the gun works.
Yeah.
In the middle of this sting,
I get some stupid award.
Dude, top seizure agent
of the year award.
CNN, in their infinite wisdom,
they send a camera crew.
So for about a week,
I've got my face plastered
all over the TV.
- Not good.
- Not good at all.
Now, we're meeting with some
of the top guys in the family.
This right here, my friends, is
the best booger sugar in cali.
Find none better.
[Speaking Spanish]
I know you.
Yeah.
Yeah, we both know Richie.
Tall guy, cockeyed.
They know they've seen my face,
but they can't place it.
Now they're getting spooked.
The TV.
Tell 'em what you said, Briggs.
Just tell 'em.
Hmm?
[Sigh] Yeah.
Yeah, it's true.
You got me.
I don't brag about it,
but I'm an actor.
Sometimes I play a cop
in the movies.
- They believed that?
- Hell, no! No.
So now we got gun barrels
jammed under our chins, right?
And I just start talking
out of my ass.
I'm sure you've seen
the trailer.
It's a movie about cops
who are undercover as hookers.
Bullsh...
No, no, no.
Hey, straight up, man.
The dude is famous.
Look, you know,
I play a cop who goes under
as a male hooker named shasta.
A hooker?
Yeah, yeah,
and how the woman I marry
turns out that her sister
is a real hooker.
Your wife's sister
is a prostitute.
Yeah.
Never said it was good movie.
You know, her pimp calls her...
calls her lowrider
because, you know,
you pull the strings
on her panties,
her ass starts like
bouncing up and down
like it's on hydraulics,
you know?
The movie ends
with nine hookers
hauling ass
down sunset boulevard
in full heels.
You know,
it's called sunset bust.
So Briggs did
the craziest thing.
They're not buying
any of this, dude.
Like none of it.
Tell him what you did.
May I show you something?
[Speaking Spanish]
Easy.
Well, basically, I know
we're screwed if they search us,
so I pull out my badge
and toss it on the bed.
Prop from the movie.
- [Laughing]
- And?
And they're looking at it,
you know, real close.
Right.
[Laughing]
[Speaking spanish] [Laughter]
It looks like something that
came out of cracker Jacks box.
Yeah!
- It's a low-budget film.
- Yeah, right.
To this day,
one of those guys still has
an autographed picture of Briggs
hanging in his cell.
[Laughing]
Wait, wait, wait.
They went through with the buy?
- Yeah, they made the buy.
- We nailed 'em all.
Hey, guys.
I gotta be in this movie.
- You sure you're ready, son?
- Come on, man.
Yeah.
Okay.
If Felix asks,
you tell him that, uh,
you play my brother-in-law.
But it ain't gonna matter,
'cause he ain't gonna ask.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
So I'm married
to the prostitute?
Ha! Yes!
Yes, you're married to, uh...
- Lowrider.
- To lowrider.
- Hydraulics.
- [Laughing]
- Ha. I hope he does ask now.
- Yeah, me too.
All right, Escobar.
I need you to put this on.
- Is this plugged in?
- Transmits everything to us.
- Ooh! No wires?
- Not since the wire.
Okay, gimme a level.
[Heightened] It's a pleasure
doing business with you.
We're not trying to play
to the balcony.
Just talk normal.
[Relaxed] Pleasure
doing business with you.
- I assume that's our bust line.
- Yeah.
Start hiring writers.
So I'm in the middle
of breakfast this morning,
and I get a call from FBI ops
asking why
they haven't been informed
that we're running a reverse
on a Vzakonye dealer.
Imagine my surprise
since I didn't know
we had a Vzakonye dealer.
We don't. Pulled him
off the list a month ago.
- And we're doing this why?
- That would be Lauren's idea.
[Scoffs]
Mike Warren, Gerry Silvo.
I'm your gs.
Oh, it's a pleasure, sir.
Let me know
how long that lasts.
It's almost noon.
Briggs taught you
everything he knows yet?
Yes, sir.
Wax on, wax off.
I assume that's an in-joke.
I don't like in-jokes.
- Understood, sir.
- Felix arroyo.
He's got a family,
so he's not likely to rip you.
He's got his wife
and kids in there.
He's not gonna start shooting.
This should be easy.
Yeah, it should be.
Mike, now remember, we're gonna
be arresting you too, okay?
So make it look good in case
his buddies are watching.
- Are you nervous?
- Yes, sir.
That's good.
Let's do this right.
Don't get shot, Mikey.
Kiss for good luck?
No.
Hey, buddy.
Is Felix here?
Dad!
[Dog barks in distance]
- Hmm.
- Hey.
Paul's friend?
Mike.
Felix.
Yeah, come on inside.
Thanks.
You, uh...
you want some lemonade?
No. Thanks.
Irina, grab us
some lemonade, baby.
So you and Paul
are friends, huh?
Yeah, yeah.
I met him, you know, around.
Yeah? Around?
Well, he's...
he's my brother-in-law.
Oh.
Nice to meet you.
I married his sister.
She's a hooker.
[Laughing] 20 bucks says
he shows 'em his badge.
God forbid.
In the movie.
[Laughs]
I play his brother-in-law
in the movie.
- You in picture with Paul?
- Yes!
[All laughing] Sorry.
I was gonna say.
My family's messed up.
But yours esta loco!
Whoo. Yeah.
- You also play cop?
- Manos arriba.
Aah!
He's funny.
Stupid.
Felix: Me and Mike are gonna
step out for a minute.
Irina: Of course.
So...
Here's the deal, man.
You know how things,
they get stacked up?
I mean,
this guy doesn't show up.
So now you can't pay that guy.
So you're short.
He doesn't have the money.
Looks like we just wasted
an afternoon, fellows.
No, I wish I was short.
I'm out!
It's the economy, you know?
My other guy...
he didn't show up for his stuff.
So... What was
the other guy buying?
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Hold on for a second.
I think the kid's
trying to save it.
So maybe you'd be interested
in some merchandise
in exchange for the indoor?
Possibly.
What are we talking about here?
Man, it's good stuff.
Go check it out, man.
It's in the alley.
Come on!
You told him not
to change locations, right?
Mike: Sure, let's go.
- No, I did not.
Damn it!
I need somebody out
in that alley right now.
Agent 1: I've lost him.
Agent 2:
Negative. No control.
Agent 1: I can't get in there
without burning it.
I can get somebody
in there on foot.
Do it.
Johnny, you were fast
in fifth grade, weren't you?
[Sighs]
Afterburners, baby.
Let's go.
Check it out.
15,000 pairs of Levi's finest.
Jeans?
And you wanna trade
straight across for the eight?
Straight up?
Come on, man.
You can get like 15 bucks a pair
on the street for these.
That's... how much is that?
180,000.
Yeah!
That's a lot of money, Mike.
Yeah, and I'll bet your wife
is chewing your ear off
to get this truck outta here.
- I'll tell you what.
- [Chuckles]
If you can make this disappear,
then you got a deal.
I'll see what I can do.
Pleasure doing business
with you, Felix.
[Laughing]
Stop! Federal bureau!
Federal bureau!
What is that guy yelling?
[Sirens blaring]
Federal bureau!
Spread it!
You're both under arrest.
Come on!
How come you weren't so damn
[Murmuring indistinctly]?
What's wrong with you, man?
Damn, I knew those jeans
were bad luck.
- Hey, nice job, rookie.
- [Laughing]
Thanks, man.
What the hell
are you idiots doing?
You're not supposed
to bring him through here!
- Mike?
- Get him outta here!
- That's messed up.
- Get him outta here.
Damn.
Hey! What happened?
- They walked Felix into Mike.
- It happened.
It's over.
[Dog whimpers] Mangy little...
You are not gonna make this
easy on me, are you?
Sergei Nayfeld.
24, Felix arroyo.
[Buzzer]
Arroyo!
Your lawyer's here.
[Buzzer]
[Whispers] Sir, sir, sir.
That man is not my lawyer.
Do not let him bail me out.
Please.
- Hey, levi.
- Levi?
Yeah, you need a nickname.
- I don't think I like levi.
- Too bad.
You don't get to choose
your nickname, do you, Johnny?
- "Johnny" is a nickname?
- Yep.
Briggs gave it to me.
It's my character in the movie.
Man, you put everyone
in the movie, don't you?
He begged.
[Laughter]
Check this.
Tuturro and Briggs
were undercover
with this biker gang.
Tuturro figures
if Briggs can do it he can too.
- Damn right.
- [Mocking laughter]
So he tells 'em that he plays
this tough-guy killer.
Yeah.
Without missing a beat,
Briggs tells him,
"yeah, the guy he shot
was sitting on the toilet."
[Laughter]
He tells them I shoot this dude
when I catch him reading
my dirty mags on the John.
Mmhmm, two slugs.
One in the arm,
one right in the chest.
Couldn't even make me
a good shot, could you?
Bikers started calling him
Johnny after that, and it stuck.
You know what, I like it.
Here's to Johnny.
Do you?
I'm glad you like it, levi.
To levi!
Levi!
To levi.
Levi.
Thank you, officer.
[Scoffs]
Wow.
I didn't know
I could afford a lawyer
with such a nice suit.
The police tell me
you're a third striker,
and I cannot bail you out.
Yeah.
Stolen jeans.
It's a tough state.
We need assurance
you will not talk to the feds.
I'm not saying nothing.
Just the same, your family
will be staying with us
until this is all over.
No. No, no, no, no.
Please.
I will do anything.
Yes, you will.
Start by telling the truth.
What is this crap
with the jeans?
It's just a side business, man.
We don't take care of you?
Who is this guy
they arrested you with?
It's my brother-in-law.
He's family.
Yeah.
- I'm unpredictable?
- Hey!
What are we celebrating?
What's up, dude?
Levi here
popped his cherry today.
Levi?
[Laughter] Yeah.
Hey, levi!
- Buy you a beer?
- Ah, no, I'm good.
Later then.
Levi.
Tell me a story, man.
A story?
Yeah.
I got no stories.
Well, let's think about that.
You just got yourself
a shiny new nickname.
Mm.
There's a gotta be
a story in that.
All right,
it was a reverse gone wrong,
and I ended up with a truckload
of knockoff jeans.
- Knockoff jeans.
- A truckload.
That is a solid story.
Yeah, you know what?
It is a good story.
What about you?
Me?
You're very protective
of your juice.
Oh, you sensing some deep
psycho-babble in that?
Stayed in that anal phase
too long?
Does not play well with others?
Wow, okay.
So you are an only child.
[Laughs] Look, man,
you caught me on a bad day.
But I bet you
tuturro was up to mischief.
He's the one
who handed you the juice.
Am I right?
I knew it.
And you didn't even rat out his
little kale-eating scrawny ass.
Respect, man.
[Music stops]
Let's start with the good news.
Turns out that truck
full of jeans
was lifted off the port.
Which makes it
customs' problem, not mine.
Congratulations, Jakes.
You are now the proud owner
of 12,000 knockoff Levi's...
[Laughter]
Courtesy of your
new bestest buddy Mike.
- We met.
- Aww. Come on, levi.
Bad news is...
You just made bail.
So we're sure
that they have Felix's family.
Yeah.
Felix panicked when the lawyer
asked him about Mike.
Said he was
his brother-in-law.
- He said what?
- Yeah. But we got lucky.
Felix does have
a brother-in-law
with a passing resemblance
to Mike.
By which I mean he's white.
Frankie bout.
We gotta do something
about your height.
He's got a scar
above his left eye,
and if it comes up, you've lost
a hell of a lot of weight.
Other than that,
he's a perfect match.
[Whispering] One minute.
Mike, come on.
So how's your new job
so far, huh?
Oh, well, it's great.
Cleaned some dishes,
learned how to surf.
So what exactly
is gonna happen here?
Kidnapping a family
is messy, Mike.
All right,
they're bailing you out
because they want assurance
that Felix won't talk.
They think you're family.
They get you to do
something illegal.
Then if Felix talks to us,
they turn you in.
Illegal.
Yeah.
Uh, we've seen them
do this before.
They're gonna ask you
to kill someone...
Mike.
Now all you gotta do
is get a name, okay?
You come back to us, that's it.
We got a guy over at the paper,
he'll play ball
with a homicide story, an obit.
They think the guy's dead,
they let the family go.
You don't have to do this.
Yeah, but if I don't,
what happens to that family?
[Sighs]
All right.
All right, we gotta assume
these Russian pricks
have the same intel we do.
You got exactly one hour
to become this guy.
Your name's Frankie bout.
You got it, Mike?
- Frankie bout.
- Yeah.
Your wife's name is Katerina.
She's Felix's wife's sister.
Her name is Irina.
Wait, wait.
Wait, my wife is Katerina
or Felix's?
Yours.
Write it down.
Sure.
You ever been to chi town?
I drove there once in college.
All right, well,
now you're from there.
So just remember wrigleyville,
sears tower, magic mile.
Your arrest in '04?
GTA. I boosted a firebird.
Nice. Wife?
Katerina.
She's a year younger than me.
Good man.
What's your name?
Mike?
- Uh...
- What's your name?
Bout. Frankie bout.
Damn it! I know that.
I know that.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait a second.
January of this year,
suspicion narco possession.
Arresting officer
noted track marks.
This guy's a junkie?
Charlie, we need a makeup job.
When's the last time
he could've gotten high?
Uh, 11:30.
You shoot up here, 'cause
your watch'll cover these up.
You haven't had a hit
in 14 hours.
You're in withdrawal,
so you're gonna be shaky.
See? You're a natural.
[Laughs]
All right, so I got a pair
of 101/2 boots
with 3-inch lifts
and a wallet for one
Frankie bout.
It's got the plastic,
money, I.D., whatever.
No, no, no.
This guy doesn't have
a gold card.
And the only thing he's doing
with a library card
is chopping his H.
This thing is brand-new.
Johnny, go... Toss it around
in the sand or something.
- You se...
- Kick it.
All right, Frankie bout,
this is your transmitter, okay?
Now we can hear you,
but you can't hear us.
Very important.
If they sweep you,
press this button.
Cuts the transmission.
Push it again to restart.
You got it?
Yeah.
You're tracking me, right?
The GPS signal's
too hard to cloak.
But we've got your audio.
Just give us as much info
about your 20 as you can
without tipping him off.
You'll be all right.
- Yes, sir.
- Mike, look at me.
Come here.
Our guy had a y-shaped scar
above his left eye.
Just pretend that Felix
came to you tonight
and said, "they took my kids.
They took my wife."
You gotta help me."
You can do this.
I like the scar.
You look tough.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Johnny, let me see that.
Come on, man.
Guy carries this in his pocket.
He doesn't drag it
behind his car.
It's dark out there, bro.
What you want?
Perfection.
- What's your name?
- Frankie bout.
What are we waiting for?
Let's do this.
Mikey!
Franklin bout,
married to the beautiful
and sexy Katerina.
Bout, Frankie.
Sign.
[Sniffles, clears throat]
You surf?
You should try it.
It kicks ass.
Mr. bout,
raise your arms, please.
- He just stopped transmitting.
- They're sweeping him.
[Wand warbles]
Thank you.
Okay, we got him back.
Nayfeld [On radio]:
You speak Russian?
No, that's my wife.
The only I understand in Russian
is "not tonight."
[Laughing] My man.
They're moving.
I'm going in on this.
No, you're not.
You set this whole thing
in motion.
Get outta here.
I can go over your head.
Yeah, you could.
But I don't want
an agent out there
looking for revenge
and neither does your boss.
Now get outta here.
Kincaid!
Sit down.
Listen in.
Who's Souren?
Oh, must be the guy
who owns the place.
Got that?
Souren's auto shop on lakewood.
[Both speaking Russian]
Frankie, right?
Have a seat.
How is Felix?
He's worried about his family.
You're also his family.
Yeah. Hmm.
You need something?
Coffee, water?
No, thanks.
I'm fine.
Benji, bring him some water.
You drop a few pounds recently?
- It's a juice cleanse.
- [Laughing]
Is that the one
where you skip the carbs
and shoot up on smack?
[Laughter]
Can, um...
Can we just get to it?
You're right.
Felix's wife and kids
should go home.
All right, well,
what do you want me to do?
[Speaking Russian]
Forget it.
Get him out of here.
- We're losing him.
- Pull him back, Mikey.
Pull him back.
Whatever you need me to do,
I can do... I can!
No, you can't!
'Cause you're goddamn junkie.
[Scoffs]
I don't want you screwing up
and blowing this back
in my face.
Come on, what,
do you want me to kill somebody?
I can kill somebody.
I've done it before.
You?
You killed someone?
Yeah.
Where's he going with this?
I wish I knew, boss.
Well, if you let Irina
and the kids go,
I'll do whatever you want.
I want you to think
very carefully
about what you're going to say
to me next, Frankie.
I've got friends
in law enforcement.
I can check details.
If you're lying to me,
I'm going to know.
You sit.
Who'd you kill?
I shot a guy while
he was sitting on the toilet.
[Laughter]
Oh, nice.
Mikey, nice!
What's nice?
The kid's gonna
get himself killed.
Okay, I need a cold case report
entered into NCIC.
This is gonna be
an unsolved homicide,
Los Angeles, two years ago.
He's ripping off my story.
No, no, no.
Johnny, he's surfing.
Where did this go down?
Los Angeles,
about two years ago.
What are you,
a mind reader now?
Somebody clue me in.
Chief.
The new kid?
He's smart.
He took my magazines...
Into the John.
Who does that?
- I'd kill him.
- [Scoffs]
- I would.
- Exactly, man.
So I let him get in there
and get settled.
I walk over to the door.
I kick it in, bam.
Pop him in the chest.
Twice.
Who's going to fight
with pants around their ankles?
- [Laughing]
- My man.
I need to check
the national database,
unsolved homicide.
All right, body found
partially clothed,
upstairs bathroom.
- Got it.
- Submit it. Let's go!
They've got some kind
of encryption block
on the NCIC server.
Just bypass their firewall.
Hit the damn send key!
What was his name?
They called him crazy Jakes.
Wait, wait!
Hold up!
Alias crazy Jakes.
Come on.
Come on, come on, come on!
Let's go.
Los Angeles homicide
said they found this guy...
Dead in his toilet, two shots,
like he said.
- Wow.
- That's what I'm talking about.
- So you whacked someone.
- Good job, good job.
[Chuckling]
[Speaking Russian]
Are you high right now?
I've been in lockup
for 14 hours.
All right.
You help us out, we'll let
the woman and the kids go.
[Speaking Russian]
All right, who's it gonna be?
A pro like you?
Let's make it a surprise.
No, wait.
Wait, whoa, whoa.
We're doing this now?
Why?
You got to be somewhere?
[Indistinct chatter]
[Car engine starting]
So where we going?
You know, Horace greeley
would not approve.
Who is Horace?
Uh, uh, Horace greeley.
Go west, young man.
They're taking him east.
It's house on left corner.
- Here's the key.
- Where'd you get this?
He has a Russian housekeeper.
It's not your problem.
Kill the man
in the back bedroom.
Be sure he's dead.
Fire all the bullets.
Bring this back to us.
502 Worthington.
I hope you guys can hear me.
We got an address.
Pull it up.
I want backup cars rolling
in that direction now!
- Got nothing on an owner.
- Bank repo? Sublet?
I need to know
what Warren's walking into.
What are you thinking?
We crash this thing with
a bunch of units rolling in...
- we lose the family.
- Yeah, at least.
I can get in there.
Yeah. Go.
[Heavy sigh]
I'm going in.
He's in the house, people.
Tell me something.
Hang on.
The house has a government tag.
- What, like wit-sec?
- Some kind of safe house.
[Hinges squeak lightly]
Excuse me.
- "Excuse me"?
- Who are you?
I'm not here to hurt you.
If that's true,
then put the gun down.
It's Donnie.
They're sending him in
to kill Donnie.
Some kid breaks into the house
with a gun, what do you do?
- I'd kill him.
- Kill him.
Lauren,
get Donnie on the phone now.
Where's my bureau chief?
Nobody wants to wake him up.
Wake everybody up.
[Phone ringing]
Put it down.
Put the gun down.
I wish I could.
[Phone ringing]
Put it down or I'm gonna
shoot you this time.
I can't.
- Who are you?
- I'm Mike Warren, FBI.
- Let's see some I.D.
- I don't have any.
Bad day for you.
Um, okay.
See these track marks?
They're fake.
I'm undercover.
Who sent you?
The Vzakonye.
They're outside this house
right now,
and they sent me
in here to kill you.
Russian bastards
aren't gonna finish me off.
Wait.
[Laughs] You're Donnie banks?
You're a lousy hit man, kid.
Just...
Where'd you get those?
- I'm your new roommate.
- You're at Graceland.
Yeah.
What else did you
take out of my room?
Uh, nothing.
Lauren... she told me
not to unpack.
Come on, man.
You gotta believe me.
It's my first day.
[Both chuckle]
You're gonna do
exactly as I do.
[Sighs]
- You transmitting?
- Yeah.
They can hear us
back at command.
Hey, guys, it's Donnie.
Met the new roommate Mike.
Almost shot him.
Yep, he almost shot me.
Oh, my God.
Yeah, you...
you almost shot me.
[Laughing]
Donnie almost shot Mike.
That's crazy.
I gotta finish this.
[Firing shots]
[Exhales] I gotta go.
Yeah, you didn't tell me
he was a goddamn DEA agent!
He took two shots at me!
- Is he dead?
- Yeah, he's dead.
Gimme the gun
and get in the car.
All right, you let the wife
and the kids go?
Yeah. Get in the car.
Yeah, you know what?
I think I'm gonna walk.
The neighbors heard the shots.
Get in the car.
Why do you want me
to get in the car?
- Don't be stupid.
- This is your last chance.
Get in the car.
Something's wrong.
- Yeah, get in the car.
- Or what?
Ugh!
[Horn honking]
Briggs?
Silvo, if you can hear me,
we need an ambulance
over here right now.
My guess...
get you to kill Donnie,
they take you out somewhere,
shoot you, make it look
like a suicide,
then if Felix ever talks,
they make sure
somebody finds your gun.
[Laughing] This is news to me.
Hey! You in the back,
show me your hands.
Now come on, guys.
It's all cool.
- Do it!
- Hey, come on.
Just do what he says, all right?
Do it now!
[Stammering] I'm okay.
Just put your hands up, okay?
Just do what he says.
What?
How did you...
Mike just cut transmission.
- You saw the gun?
- Yeah, I see it right there.
He's back.
This is agent Warren.
Shots fired.
Two men down.
Where's the ambulance?
Agent Briggs saved my life.
[Birds calling]
Female reporter: A morning raid
at the Russian Vzakonye cartel
by a joint federal task force
resulted in several
key arrests today.
The raid came after a firefight
between federal agents
and members of the cartel
that left
one cartel member injured...
Don't let it go
to your head, Mike.
Ha. No, ma'am.
We did good.
Hell, yeah, we did good!
Hey! Hey!
Sophia!
[Mellow pop music]
♪
Thanks.
The driver made a move
to his weapon,
and that's
when agent Briggs fired?
Yes, ma'am.
And you both ordered the man
in back to show his hands,
and instead he drew his weapon?
Correct again.
Agent Warren?
Yes, ma'am.
Sounds like
a clean shoot to me.
So are we good here?
- Briggs?
- Yeah, I'm good.
Warren, anything to add?
No, ma'am.
We're good.
- Excellent work, both of you.
Both: Thank you.
[Mellow pop song]
♪
[Laughter]
All right, man.
Glasses up.
Oh, man.
Now look,
as rookies, we all bought dope.
Some of us even on the job,
actually.
[Laughter]
But today was one to remember.
Cheers.
- Thank you.
- Yup.
Mm!
[Laughing]
No, no. Wait.
Too much studying,
not enough partying.
No, no, no.
Listen.
Back east,
we don't dance with it.
We just drink it.
- Oh, okay.
- Oh, really?
I wanna let you know no matter
how much bitching Silvo does,
you did good today.
- Thank you, sir.
- Yeah.
That means a lot.
Well, you know, Mike,
you are now an undercover agent
for the bureau, okay?
That means from this moment on,
your lies are your life.
Yes, sir.
You know,
you're out on the street.
You meet some fine little
love 'n' touch.
You better lie to her.
You know, your parents
call you on a Sunday afternoon,
"hey, Mike,
what you working on?"
You lie to 'em.
Hmm.
How do you do it though?
I mean, how do you...
the lies.
How do you just keep
from going crazy, you know?
Who says I haven't?
No one, sir.
[Phone ringing]
Mind if I take this?
- Hey, it's your party.
- Thanks.
- Hey-yo!
- Where are you going?
- Just gimme...
- I told you the boy
does not know how to party.
Yo, Mike!
Agent Campbell.
You were very right.
There's no way
I could've predicted this.
Ah, you actually listened
to my speech.
You know, I did.
Agent Briggs saved your life.
That true?
Yes, sir, he did.
I'm calling to let you know
that your assignment
is to investigate Briggs.
Will what he did
affect that ability?
- No, sir.
- Good.
Keep that attitude,
and you'll still
make deputy director one day.
I appreciate that, sir.
Keep your head down, Mike.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
[Beep]
Hey.
We're missing you over there.
Oh.
You know, uh,
I heard they kinda slammed you
with this job, huh?
Tchh. Yeah.
Yeah, they did.
Mm.
D.C. one minute, the next
you got sand in your shoes.
No idea why?
No, sir.
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
www.tvsubtitles.net